Inventory of the Records of Joseph Dupuy Eggleston 1913-1919
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Records of Joseph Dupuy Eggleston 1913-1919
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
RG 2/7
6.0 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is without restrictions.
Biographical Information
Eggleston became the seventh president of Virginia Polytechnic Institute (VPI) in 1913. His six-year administration was most notably marked by the development of the agricultural extension program at VPI. In 1914, the Agricultural Extension Division was established. The Virginia General Assembly transferred control of agricultural demonstration work to VPI, so the Home Demonstration program began in 1915. Much of Eggleston's presidential tenure was during the years of World War I. The college became a training school for both the army and navy during this time. A Reserve Officer Training Corps (ROTC) program was established at VPI in 1916. In January 1919, the college was designated by the War Department as one of twelve "Distinguished Colleges" in the nation for its contribution to the war effort. In the spring of 1919, Eggleston resigned to become president of Hampden-Sydney College, his alma mater.
Scope and Content Information
The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence (1913-19) including: letters to and from state and national political figures; correspondence signed by Eggleston as Acting Director of the Extension Division (1913-16); correspondence between Eggleston and principals, board members and others of various agricultural high schools relating to financial requests, personnel, etc. (1916-19); correspondence with county agents and state and national personnel connected with agricultural programs; correspondence with Carneal and Johnston, architects, concerning construction of Shop building, Gymnasium, Professor Vawter's residence, VPI Chapel, McBryde building, Athletic building, and Field House. Other material in the collection includes: Sophomore Court matters (1913-14); reports of annual meetings of agents (1913-16); Agricultural Experiment Station reports (1914); U.S.D.A. Weekly Demonstration Work Reports (1914); financial forecasts (1914-15); annual reports (1915); Smith-Lever salary vouchers, 1915; reports of demonstration agents (1916); departmental needs (1917); telegrams (1917-19); resolution creating Athletic Director position (1918); Houston property deeds and contracts; speeches and articles. Education for women and African American extension and Y. M. C. A. work are among the issues addressed in the correspondence.
Arrangement
Arrangement
The collection has been kept in the original order in which it was received even though this order in not consistently alphabetical or chronological. The headings on the original folders were retained in the inventory even though the language at times is archaic, as in the use of the word "colored."
Organization
This collection has been divided into three separate series.
Contents List
- Series I
  - Appropriations Commitee, House of Delegates, Richmond, Va. (Box-folder 1-1)
    Letter concerning a summer session at VMI.
  - Agnew Ella 1913-1914 (Box-folder 1-2)
    Letter concerning the organization of vocational classes for women.
  - Agnew, Ella 1914-February 1916 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Agnew, Ella (charges against Rhea Scott) 1916 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Rhea E. Scott 1914-1916 (Box-folder 1-5)
    Notable letterhead of the Hotel Roanoke.
  - Agents--reports of annual meetings 1914-1916 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Reports of industrial agents 1916 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Boy's Club 1915 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - African-American ("Colored") Works 1916 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - African-American (Negro) Homemaker Clubs--rural schools (Box-folder 1-10)
  - Demonstration Work (Box-folder 1-11)
    Includes reports on African-American agents; notable letterhead of H.O. Lyne, merchant miller; and flier for Loves Mill school fair.
  - Extension Work 1914 (Box-folder 1914)
  - Financial Forecast 1914-1915 (Box-folder 1-13)
  - Projects--Extension Works 1914-1916 (Box-folder 1-14)
  - Hog Cholera matters 1914 (Box-folder 1-15)
  - Burruss, W.H. 1915 (Box-folder 1-16)
  - Correspondence--Hays, Jones 1914 (Box-folder 1-17)
    Houston Deed (1914)
  - Fletcher, S.W. 1910-1914 (Box-folder 1-18)
  - Truck Experiment Station report 1914 (Box-folder 1-19)
  - Hutcheson, J.R. 1913-1915 (Box-folder 1-20)
  - Correspondence--Bunch, Garnett 1914 (Box-folder 1-21)
  - Jones, Jesse M. 1915 (Box-folder 1-22)
  - Bradford Knapp 1913-July 1914 (Box-folder 1-23)
  - Bradford Knapp 1914 (Box-folder 1-24)
  - Knapp, Bradford 1915 (Box-folder 1-25)
  - A.C. True 1914-1915 (Box-folder 1-26)
  - Whately--Wilson and Waters 1914 (Box-folder 1-27)
  - J. Kingborne 1914-1915 (Box-folder 1-28)
  - A.C. Monahan--R.W. Roberts, Stemmons (Box-folder 1-29)
  - Wysor,W.G. 1915 (Box-folder 1-30)
  - Sandy T.O. 1913-1914 (Box-folder 1-31)
  - Sandy T.O. 1915 (Box-folder 1-32)
    Notable letterhead of Norfolk and Western Railway Company
  - Smith Lever (State Resolution) 1914 (Box-folder 1-33)
    Signed letter from Booker T. Washington (1914)
  - J.A.C. Chandler 1917-1918 (Box-folder 1-34)
    Notable letterhead of Richmond Public Schools
  - Appomattox 1916-1919 (Box-folder 1-35)
    Includes notable letterhead of Appomattox Barred Rock Association and notable letterhead of Dixie Fire Insurance Company.
  - Burkeville 1917-1919 (Box-folder 1-36)
    Notable letterhead of Hotel Rueger
  - Charlotte C.H. (Court House) 1916-1919 (Box-folder 1-37)
    Notable letterhead of Murphy's Hotel
  - Chase City 1917-1919 (Box-folder 1-38)
    Notable letterhead of Hotel Stumpf
  - Chester 1918 (Box-folder 1-39)
  - Claremont 1918 (Box-folder 1-40)
  - Dinwiddie 1918-1919 (Box-folder 1-41)
  - Driver 1916-1919 (Box-folder 1-42)
    Includes notable letterhead of Delco-Light Products and notable letterhead of Murphy's Hotel.
  - S.P. Duke 1918 (Box-folder 1-43)
  - Thomas D. Eason 1918-1919 (Box-folder 1-44)
  - Elk Creek 1916-1918 (Box-folder 1-45)
  - Hampton 1916-1919 (Box-folder 1-46)
  - Harris Hart, superintendent, Roanoke City Public Schools (Box-folder 1-47)
  - J.R. Hutcheson--report on equipment needed in agricultural high school; Chandler, Dr. J.A.C., superintendent of schools, Richmond 1918 (Box-folder 1-48)
  - Lebanon 1916-1918 (Box-folder 1-49)
  - Lincoln 1916 (Box-folder 1-50)
  - Mannassas 1916-1918 (Box-folder 1-51)
  - Middletown 1916-1917 (Box-folder 1-52)
    Includes notable letterhead of the Commonwealth of Virginia, House of Delegates; as well as notable letterhead of the Commonwealth of Virginia, State Chamber.
  - New London 1916-1918 (Box-folder 1-53)
  - Tubeville 1916-1919 (Box-folder 1-54)
    Includes notable letterhead from R.C. Beverly Heating Company.
  - Pertersnurg--Virginia Normal and Industrial Institute (Box-folder 1-55)
    Includes notable letterhead of Virginia Normal and Industrial Institute.
  - Glass, Carter 1917 (Box-folder 1-56)
  - Graham, H.T. 1917 (Box-folder 1-57)
  - Greene, George O. 1916 (Box-folder 1-58)
  - G-Miscellaneous 1917z (Box-folder 1-59)
    Includes notable letterhead of Maryland State Board of Agriculture.
  - Hall, J. Leslie 1916 (Box-folder 1-60)
  - Hardwicke, J.T. 1917 (Box-folder 1-61)
  - H-miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 1-62)
  - J-miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 1-63)
  - James, R.A.; Juntulo, P.U. 1917 (Box-folder 1-64)
  - Jarman, J.B. 1916-1917 (Box-folder 1-65)
  - Johnson T.C. 1916 (Box-folder 2-66)
  - Kent, Chas W. 1917 (Box-folder 2-67)
  - Koiner, George W. 1917 (Box-folder 2-68)
    Includes notable letterhead of Commonwealth of Virginia, Department of Agriculture and Immigration.
  - K-miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 2-69)
    Includes notable letterhead of Central Fredrick Farmer's Club.
  - LaBaume, F.H. 1917 (Box-folder 2-70)
    Includes notable letterhead of Norfolk and Western Immigration Association.
  - Lucas, J.B. 1917 (Box-folder 2-71)
  - L-miscellaneous 1916-1917 (Box-folder 2-72)
  - McBryde, J.M. 1-73 (Box-folder 2-73)
  - McConnell, J.P. 1917 (Box-folder 2-74)
  - McLauring, Dr. R.E. 1917 (Box-folder 2-75)
  - McIlwain, Dr. H.R. 1917 (Box-folder 2-76)
  - Martin, Senator Thos. S. 1917=1918 (Box-folder 2-77)
  - Mason, Guy Massie Bland 1917 (Box-folder 2-78)
    Includes notable letthead of League to Enforce Peace.
  - Maphis, Charles G. 1917 (Box-folder 2-79)
  - Miller, W.W. 1917 (Box-folder 2-80)
  - Moomaw, B.C. 1917 (Box-folder 2-81)
    Includes notable letterhead of Virginia Agricultural Council of Safety.
  - Montgomery, J.H. 1916-1918 (Box-folder 2-82)
    Includes notable letterhead of Co-Operative Education Association of Virginia.
  - Moore, E.S. 1917 (Box-folder 2-83)
    Includes notable letterhead of Norfolk and Western Railway Company.
  - Munford, Mrs. B.B. 1917 (Box-folder 2-84)
    includes notable letterhead of Co-Operative Education Assciation of Virginia.
  - M--Miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 2-85)
    Includes notable letterhead of Merchants National Bank of Richmond, notable letterhead of United Daughters of the Confederacy, and notable letterhead of Daleville College
  - Ackley, S.A. 1917 (Box-folder 2-86)
  - Alderman, E.A. 1917 (Box-folder 2-87)
  - Aewell, J.B. 1917 (Box-folder 2-88)
  - A-miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 2-89)
  - Battle, Geo. Gordan 1917 (Box-folder 2-90)
  - "Uncle Bill" (William Gitt) 1917 (Box-folder 2-91)
  - Bingham, Robert 1917 (Box-folder 2-92)
  - Branch, John Kerr 1917 (Box-folder 2-93)
  - Atkinson, Thomas W. 1916-1917 (Box-folder 1916-1917)
  - Brown, David H., American Red Cross 1917 (Box-folder 2-95)
  - J. Stewart Bryan 1917 (Box-folder 2-97)
  - J.A. Burruss 1917 (Box-folder 2-98)
  - R.E. Byrd 1916-1917 (Box-folder 2-99)
  - B--miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 2-100)
    Includes notable letterhead of Baptist Church, Wythville, Va.
  - Carlin, C.C. 1917 (Box-folder 2-101)
  - Chapman, H. Powell 1917 (Box-folder 2-102)
  - Cooper, L.M. 1917 (Box-folder 2-103)
  - C--Miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 2-104)
    Includes notable letterhead of the James River Clarion
  - Dabney, C.W. 1917 (Box-folder 2-105)
  - Davis, Miss J.E. 1917 (Box-folder 2-106)
  - Davis, Westmoreland 1917 (Box-folder 2-107)
  - Denney, R.E. 1917 (Box-folder 2-108)
  - D--miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 2-109)
  - Ehart, F.W. 1917 (Box-folder 2-110)
  - Ferguson, Meade; Ferneyhough, J.G. 1917 (Box-folder 2-111)
  - Flanagan, Ray K. 1917 (Box-folder 2-112)
    Includes notable letterhead of Department of Health, Richmond, VA
  - Flood, Hal D. 1917 (Box-folder 2-113)
  - Forward, Alexander 1917 (Box-folder 2-114)
    Includes notable letterhead of Commonwealth of Virginia, Governor's Office.
  - Ford, Henry C.; W.D. Frith 1917 (Box-folder 2-115)
  - Gibbaney, J.H. 1917 (Box-folder 2-116)
  - Sparta, Toano 2-117 (Box-folder 2-117)
  - Varino District (Henrico County) 1919 (Box-folder 2-118)
    Includes notable letterhead of Sydnor Pump and Well Company
  - Wakefield 1919 (Box-folder 2-119)
  - Whitmell; Williamsburg 1918-1919 (Box-folder 2-120)
  - Windsor 1919 (Box-folder 2-121)
    Includes notable letterhead of Commonwealth of Virginia, House of Delegates
  - Woodlawn 1919 (Box-folder 2-122)
  - B--Miscellaneous 1916 (Box-folder 2-123)
  - C-D-E--Miscellaneous 1916 (Box-folder 2-124)
  - F-G-H--Miscellaneous 1915-1916 (Box-folder 2-125)
  - Ferguson, S.L 1917 (Box-folder 2-126)
    Includes notable letterhead of Commonwealth of Virginia, House of Delegates; as well as, notable letterhead of Murphy's Hotel.
  - Dr. C.H. Hayes 1916 (Box-folder 2-127)
    United States Department of Agriculture
  - Hutcheson J.R. 1916 (Box-folder 2-128)
  - J-K-L-M--miscellaneous 1916 (Box-folder 2-129)
  - Jones, Jesse M. 1916 (Box-folder 2-130)
  - Knapp, Dr. Bradford 1916 (Box-folder 2-131)
  - F.M. McLaughlin 1916 (Box-folder 2-132)
  - D.B. Martin 1916 (Box-folder 2-133)
  - Pierce, J.B. 1916 (Box-folder 2-134)
  - S-T-V-W--miscellaneous 1916 (Box-folder 2-135)
    Includes notable letterhead of Stacy's Poultry Farm
  - N Miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 2-136)
  - N-O-P-R--miscellaneous 2-137 (Box-folder 2-137)
    Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station
  - D--Miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 2-138)
  - Page, Dr. J.M. 1917-1918 (Box-folder 2-139)
  - Payne, Bruce R. 1917 (Box-folder 2-140)
  - Pollard, John Garland 1917 (Box-folder 2-141)
    Commonwealth of Viginia, Office of the Attorney General; Commonwealth of Virginia, Auditor of Public Accounts
  - Price, E.R. 1917 (Box-folder 2-142)
  - Price, H.R. 1917 (Box-folder 2-143)
  - Priddy, Lawrence 1917 (Box-folder 2-144)
    Includes notable letterhead of the New Willard Hotel, Washington
  - Purcel, Benjamin L. 1916-1917 (Box-folder 2-145)
    Commonwealth of Virginia, Dairy and Feed Division
  - P--Miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 2-146)
    Includes notable letterhead of Hatcher-Perry Company, INC.; United States Deapartment of Agriculture;notable letterhead of Richmond Automobile Club; notable letterhead of Carolina Hotel; notable letterhead of the Law Offices of Pollard and Smith; notable letterhead of Aerial League of America; and Shops Department, Virginia Polytechnic Institute.
  - Ridsdale, P.S.; Riggs, W.M.; Roller, John B. 1917 (Box-folder 2-147)
  - Roop, R.I. 1917 (Box-folder 2-148)
  - Ruffin, J.R. 1917 (Box-folder 2-149)
  - Russell, E.H.; Russell, J.S. 1917 (Box-folder 2-150)
  - R--miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 2-151)
  - Scott, C.B.; Settle, T.S. 1917 (Box-folder 2-152)
    Virginia Road Builders' Association
  - Skawkey, M.P.; Shepard, B.M.; Shelton, Farrar; Shoemaker, C.V. 1917 (Box-folder 2-153)
  - Smith, Henry 1917 (Box-folder 2-154)
  - Spangler, D.E. 1917 (Box-folder 2-155)
  - State Farmer's Institute 1917 (Box-folder 2-156)
  - Staytom, W.H. 1917 (Box-folder 2-157)
  - Superintendent--Montgomery County 1917 (Box-folder 2-158)
    Richmond Public Schools
  - Swanson, Claude 1917 (Box-folder 2-159)
  - S--Miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 2-160)
    Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Department of Modern Languages; Norfolk and Wesern Railway Company; Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station
  - Stuart, Henry C. 1917 (Box-folder 2-161)
    Commonwealth of Virginia, Governor's Office
  - Thomas, J.S. 1917 (Box-folder 2-162)
  - Times-Dispach; Trout, H.H.; Tucker, H. St. George;Tyler, Lyon G. 1917 (Box-folder 2-163)
    Includes notable letterhead from the Times-Dispatch
  - T--Miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 2-164)
  - U--Miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 2-165)
  - Vaughn, J.L.; Villard, O.G. 1917 (Box-folder 2-166)
  - Veale, F.R. 1916-1917 (Box-folder 2-167)
  - V--miscellaneous 1916-1917 (Box-folder 2-168)
  - Watson, W.A.; Weatherford, W.D. 1917 (Box-folder 2-169)
    Notable letterhead of the Southern Summer School
  - Werth, J.R. 1917 (Box-folder 2-170)
    Notable letterhead of National Electric Association and Army and Navy Young Men's Christian Association
  - Williams, E.G.; Winfrey, G.H.; Wilson, J.S. 1917 (Box-folder 2-171)
  - Wood, N.O. 1917 (Box-folder 2-172)
  - Woodfin, S.B. 1917 (Box-folder 2-173)
    Includes notable letterhead for the Richmond Virginian
  - Worthington Pump and Machinery Company 1917 (Box-folder 2-174)
    Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Department of Mechanical Engineering
  - Wright, A.D. (Box-folder 3-175)
    State Board of Education, Department of Public Education
  - Yerby, Emma S. 1917 (Box-folder 3-176)
  - W--Miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 3-177)
    Co-Operative Education Association of America; National Security League, Committee on Patriotism through Education
  - Y--Miscellaneous 1917 (Box-folder 3-178)
  - T.O. Sandy 1915-February 1916 (Box-folder 3-179)
  - T.O. Sandy March-June 1916 (Box-folder 3-180)
  - N.E.B. Talcott 1916 (Box-folder 3-181)
  - True, Dr. A.C. 1916 (Box-folder 3-182)
  - Vrooman, Hon. Carl 1915-1916 (Box-folder 3-183)
  - Speeches and Articles 1914-1915; 1917; 1947-1948 (Box-folder 3-184)
    "Meeting Much interest: The Demonstration Train Has Many Visitors in the Southwest;" "A Land of Opportunity:What Demonstration Work Is Doing for the State;" Tribute Paid to Professor Davidson;" Eggleston's accomplishments as Superintendent of Public instruction of Virginia;" "What Is 4-H Club Work;" "An Extract from President Eggleston's Address to the Graduating Class, May 31, 1917"
  - A's 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-185)
  - Application 1914 (Box-folder 3-186)
  - Banks, Bruce A. 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-187)
  - Boulware, A.L--Smithfield 1914-1916 (Box-folder 3-188)
  - Burruss, J.A., president, Harrisonburg Normal 1913-1914; 1916 (Box-folder 3-189)
    State Normal School, Harrisonburg, VA; Virginia State Teacher's Association, Office of President
  - Denny, G.H., president--University of Alabama 1913-1914, 1916 (Box-folder 3-190)
  - Lime--controversy over cast quality 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-191)
    Virginia Polytechnic Institute Department of Chemistry
  - Glass, Carter 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-192)
  - F--miscellaneous 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-193)
  - Flanagan, R.K., Board of Health 1914 (Box-folder 3-194)
    Commonwealth of Virginia, State Board of Health, Bureau of Inspections
  - Eggleston, J.D. 1913-1919 (Box-folder 3-195)
    Includes notable letterhead from Equal Suffrage League of Virginia; notable letterhead from the Lynchburg News; State Normal and Industrial School for Women at Fredricksburg, VA; notable letterhead from Alleghany Ore and Iron Co.; Norfolk & Western Railway Company; notable letterhead from the Great Radford Fair, and N & W Operates Farming Train
  - Deeds and Contracts--Houston Property 1914,1917 (Box-folder 3-196)
  - Insurance 1914 (Box-folder 3-197)
    Include notable letterhead from National Fire and Insurance Company of Hartford, CT
  - Governor Mann 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-198)
    Commonweath of Virginia, Governor's Office
  - Maphis, Chas G. 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-199)
    Includes notable letterhead from La Fayette Hotel
  - Martin, T.S. 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-200)
  - McConnell, J.P. 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-201)
  - Messer, Richard 1913 (Box-folder 3-202)
    Commonwealth of Virginia, State Board of Health, Bureau of Sanitary Engineering; Commonwealth of Virginia, Department of Health
  - Munford, Mrs. B.B. 1913 (Box-folder 3-202)
    Co-operative Education Association of Virginia
  - M--Miscellaneous 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-204)
    Grand Lodge of Virginia I.O.O.F., Office of Grand Secretary; Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Department of animal Husbandry and Veterinary Science; Virgina Agricultural Experiment Station
  - North Carolina A & M 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-205)
  - N--Miscellaneous 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-206)
    Includes notable letterhead from Orange Judd Company and notable letterhead from Portsmouth Buisnessmen's Association
  - Polland, John Garland--Attorney General 1914 (Box-folder 3-207)
    Commonwealth of Virginia, Office of the Attorney General
  - Purcell, B.L. 1914 (Box-folder 3-208)
    Commonwealth of Virginia, Dairy and Food Division
  - P--Miscellaneous 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-209)
  - Rural Economics Development 1914 (Box-folder 3-210)
  - R--miscellaneous 1914 (Box-folder 3-211)
    Virginia Anti-Tuberculosis Association
  - Smithfield 1914,1916 (Box-folder 3-212)
  - Stuart, Henry C.--Governor 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-213)
    Commonwealth of Virginia, Governor's Office; Natoinal Soil Fertility League
  - Student Loan Fund 1914 (Box-folder 3-214)
    Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Office of the President
  - Swanson, Claude--Senator 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-215)
  - S--miscellaneous 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-216)
  - Teeth 1914 (Box-folder 3-217)
  - Telephone Development 1913-1916 (Box-folder 3-218)
  - T--miscellaneous 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-219)
  - W--Miscellaneous 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-220)
  - Ackley; Addison; Alderman; Allen; Anderson; Andrews 1914-1915 (Box-folder 3-221)
    Commonwealth of Virginia, Senate Chamber
  - B--Miscellaneous 1915 (Box-folder 3-222)
    Norfolk & Western Railway Company, Office of the General Claim Agent, Casulty Department
  - Bell Co.; Binford; Burkhart; J.A. Burruss; R.E. Byrd 1915 (Box-folder 3-223)
    Notable letterhead from the J.P. Bell Company, INC; State Normal and Industrial School, Hariisonburg, Virginia, Appointment Committee; State Normal and Industrial School, Harrisonburg, VA, Office of the President; Co-operative Education Association of Virginia
  - Bocock, Brach 1914-1916 (Box-folder 2-224)
    Virginia Polytechnice Institute Athletic Association; Virginia Polytechnice Institute Departmen of Mathematics; Virginia Polytechnic Institute Office of the Secretary of the Faculty; Virginia Agricutural Experiment Station
  - A.B. Bourland 1915 (Box-folder 3-225)
    Southern Conference for Education and Industry
  - Campbell, T.P. Jr.; Cannon Jos.; Chandler, A.B. Jr. 1915 (Box-folder 3-226)
    Includes notable letterhead from the London Assurance Corporation
  - Chesterman, E.R. 1915 (Box-folder 3-227)
    State Board of Education, Deparment of Public Instruction; Virginia Polytechnic Institute Office of the President
  - Coggin, W.B. 1915 (Box-folder 3-228)
  - Davis, Jackson 1914-1915 (Box-folder 3-229)
    State Board of Education, Department of Public Instruction; Co-Operative Education Association; Notable letterhead from Hotel Main; General Education Board; Notable letterhead form Hotel Zinzendorf
  - Westmoreland; Davis; J.B.L. De Jaretto; Ehart; Ferguson; Ferguson Pb. Co. 1914-1915 (Box-folder 3-230)
    Virginia State Livestock Sanitary Board
  - Flanagan; Fletcher; Flexnor; Flood; Ford; Forward; F-miscellaneous 1915 (Box-folder 3-231)
    Commonwealth of Virginia, Governor's Office; National Institution for Moral Instruction; notable letterhead from the Fastoria Incandescent Lamp Division; National Lamp Works of General Electirc Company
  - Gibboney; Gritt ("Uncle Bill"); Glass; Gray; Gregory 1915 (Box-folder 3-232)
    Norfolk & Western Railway Company; Notable letterhead from R.F. Johnson Publishing Company; Notable letterhead from Chase City Manufacturing Company
  - Gass, Mrs. Leonard A. 1914-1915 (Box-folder 3-233)
    Farmer's Wife; Smith-Lever Law; Farm women's interests
  - Harris, J.D. 1915 (Box-folder 3-234)
  - Hardwicke; Hay; Hebden; Holland 1915 (Box-folder 3-235)
    Includes notable letterhead from the Hotel Richmond and notable letterhead from The Alvarado.
  - Hart; Harris 1915 (Box-folder 3-236)
  - J.P. Harvey; Dr. W.F. Henderson; E.R. Hodgeson 1913-1915 (Box-folder 3-237)
  - Houston D.F. Secretary of Agriculture, U.S.D.A. 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3-238)
    Changes in the Virginia Experiment Station
  - La Baume; L--Miscellaneous; McConnell; McKelway;Maphis;Mononi 1915 (Box-folder 3-239)
    Includes notable letterhead from the Souther Expess Company and notable letterhead from the Greenville Sun.
  - Irvine; Johnson, J.E.; Jones, R.S. 1915 (Box-folder 3-240)
    Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Department of Experimental Engineering; Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Office of the Commandant
  - Keezell, G.B.; Kemp; Koiner (Box-folder 3-241)
    Commonwealth of Virginia, Commission of Fisheries; Notable letterhead from A.W. Kemp, INC.; Commonwealth of Virginia, Department of Agriculture and Immigration
  - Martin, T.S. 1915 (Box-folder 3-242)
  - Montgomery; Munford; M--Miscellaneous; Nelson, H.T.; Owens, R.W.; O--Miscellaneous 1914-1915 (Box-folder 3-243)
    Co-Operative Education Association of Virginia; Virginia State Teacher's Association, Office of the Vice-President
  - Page; Pierce; Pollard; Purcell; P--Miscellaneous 1915 (Box-folder 3-244)
    Commonwealth of Virginia, Dairy and Feed Division; Lawrence Priddy Insurance
  - Read; Richards; Ritchie; Robinson; R--Miscellaneous 1915 (Box-folder 3-245)
    Includes notable letterhead from Murphy's Hotel as well as notalble letterhead from Hotel Richmond